{
    "id": "75ac2533900c455780a86ef57aec9d89",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "His grandfather is …………………………..",
            "description": "Dead is an adjective. Died is a verb. Adjectives can be used as subject complements. ",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "dead"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a1bc71eaa286460d911d40f754cb618f"
        },
        {
            "question": "His grandparents have ………………………………",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "died",
                "dead"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "806492c0a4fd41138360b2b147092297"
        },
        {
            "question": "He ………………………………. in",
            "description": "The present perfect is not used with past time expressions.",
            "answers": [
                "has graduated",
                "graduated",
                "had graduated"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "834bafba9ad34782bceabfac71fe2736"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ………………………………. me of her mother.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "reminds",
                "remembers"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "52964272b3264bac82a708ef601f729c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He …………………………… me a visit.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "made",
                "gave",
                "paid"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a5d548f413594b288075b49962219f23"
        },
        {
            "question": "He objected …………………………… sitting there.",
            "description": "A pronoun used to modify a gerund is usually in its possessive form.",
            "answers": [
                "to me",
                "to my",
                "me"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4177229dac1a4aad935a73ee37ea4081"
        },
        {
            "question": "We are looking forward to …………………………….. you soon.",
            "description": "We use an ing form after look forward to.",
            "answers": [
                "meet",
                "meeting"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "bfec781d59e747a4bbe9eb9ad00e22df"
        },
        {
            "question": "How …………………………………. boy he is!",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "a foolish",
                "foolish a"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "67aae25f152a48f2ab78da418d72a14c"
        },
        {
            "question": "Tell me where ………………………………..",
            "description": "In indirect questions, the subject goes before the auxiliary verb.",
            "answers": [
                "are you going",
                "you are going"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "05d8f690fd1b4db59151edf534850ba0"
        },
        {
            "question": "You had better ………………………………… another application.",
            "description": "Had better is followed by an infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "send",
                "to send",
                "sent"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c911b776b00d41b396f863e40fc10e6b"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you went there, you ………………………………… see him.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "953180f8873f438bba7c15f1b221ae18"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ............................... this, I would be wrong.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "do",
                "did"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "37040b298f8d4d40913590e7ca5d0c58"
        }
    ]
}